[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everybody.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
I'm very excited to be here
很高兴今天能在这里
today to talk about
与大家探讨
understanding ARKit Tracking and
ARKit 的跟踪与检测功能
Detection to empower you to
将如何创造出更好
create great augmented reality
的 AR（增强现实）体验
My name is Marion and I'm from
我是 Marion
the ARKit Team.
我来自 ARKit 团队
And what about you?
你呢
Are you an experienced ARKit
你是一位对 ARKit 的发展有着
interested in what's going on
浓厚兴趣的
under the hood?
资深 ARKit 开发者吗
Then, this talk is for you.
那么这个演讲就是为你准备的
Or you may be new to ARKit.
刚刚接触 ARKit
Then, you'll learn different
那从这次演讲中 你将会学到
kind of tracking technologies,
不同的跟踪技巧以及
as well as some basics and
一些 AR 常用的
terminology used in augmented
基本知识与术语
reality, which will then help
这些基本知识与术语
you to create your very own
能帮助你创造属于你
first augmented reality
自己的第一份 AR 的体验
So, let's get started.
让我们开始吧
What's tracking?
跟踪指的是什么
Tracking provides your camera
跟踪将提供你的相机
viewing position and orientation
在真实世界中
into your physical environment,
观察位置与方向
which will then allow you to
有了这些位置与方向
augment virtual content into
你就可以在你的相机中
your camera's view.
加入增强视觉的因素
In this video, for example, the
比如在这个视频中
front table and the chairs is
在真实的物理平台上的
virtual content augmented on top
桌子和椅子
of the real physical terrace.
是增强视觉的虚拟内容
This, by the way, is Ikea.
顺便说一下 这个是宜家
And the virtual content will
需要注意的是 视觉内容
appear always virtually correct.
从视觉上看都是正确的
Correct placement, correct size,
正确的放置位置 正确的大小
and correct perspective
以及正确的透视角度
So, different tracking
因此不同的跟踪
technologies are just providing
技术能为相机
a difference reference system
提供不同的参考系
Meaning the camera with respect
这意味着相机相对于
to your world, the camera with
你的世界参考系
respect to an image, or maybe, a
相机相对于图像或者 3D 物品的参考
And we'll talk about those
在接下来这一个小时里
different kind of tracking
我们将会讨论
technologies in the next hour,
不同类型的跟踪技术
such that you'll be able to make
这样子你就可以
the right choice for your
针对你的特定用例
specific use case.
做出正确的选择
We'll talk about the already
我们将会讨论
existing AR technologies'
现在已有的 AR 技术
Orientation Tracking, World
这包括 方向跟踪
Tracking, and Plane Detection.
世界跟踪 以及 平面检测
Before we then have a close look
之后 我们才会进一步
at our new tracking and
分析 ARKit 2 上
detection technologies which
自带的新的
came out now with ARKit 2.
跟踪和检测技术
Which are saving and loading
这些技术包括 保存和加载地图
maps, image tracking, and object
图像跟踪以及物品检测
But before diving deep into
在我们对这些
those technologies, let's start
技术做进一步的探讨之前
with a very short recap of ARKit
不妨先来对 ARKit 进行一个
like on a high level.
简单的概括性的回顾
This is, specifically,
这对刚刚接触 ARKit 的人来说会
ARKit.
很有趣
So, the first thing you'll do is
首先 你需要创造
create an ARSession.
一个 ARSession
An ARSession is the object that
ARSession 是处理
handles everything from
从配置到运行 AR 技术
configuring to running the AR
所有事务的对象
And also, returning the results
并且返回 AR 技术的结果
You then, have to describe what
然后你需要做的是
kind of technologies you
描述你想要运行的技术类型
Like, what kind of tracking
比如说 你想要使用
technologies and what kind of
哪种跟踪技术或者
features should be enabled, like
想要启用哪种功能
Plane Detection, for example.
比如说平面检测功能
You'll then, take this specific
接下来 你需要使用这一
ARConfiguration and call run
特定的 ARConfiguration
method on your instance of the
并运行你自己的
ARSession.
ARSession 实例
Then, the ARSession, internally,
然后 ARsession 会开始内部
will start configuring an
配置 AVCaptureSession
AVCaptureSession to start
并开始接受图像
receiving the images, as well as
以及启动动作管理器
receiving the motion sensor, so,
接收运动传感数据
data.
这就是你设备
built-in input system from your
上内置的 ARKit 输入系统
Now, after processing the
数据经过处理后
results are returned in ARFrames
会返回为每秒 60 帧
at 60 frames per second.
的 ARFrames
An ARFrame is a snapshot in time
ARFrame 是一种及时快照
which gives you everything you
它能为你的
need to render your augmented
AR 景象提供
reality scene.
所需要的一切
Like, the captured camera image,
就好像 你拍摄的图像
which would then be, which will
会成为你的 AR 场景的背景
As well as a track camera
跟踪相机运动
motion, which will then be
适用于调整虚拟相机
to render the virtual content
使之能从
from the same perspective as the
物理相机的角度
physical camera.
调整虚拟物品的角度
It also contains information
它还能提供
about the environment.
环境相关信息
Like, for example, detected
举个例子 它可以检测到盘子
planes.
现在 让我们
first tracking technology and
从第一个跟踪技术开始
build up from there.
说起和构建
Orientation Tracking.
方向跟踪
Orientation Tracking tracks,
你们觉得方向跟踪所跟踪
guess what?
的是什么呢
Orientation.
方向
Meaning it tracks the rotation,
说明它只跟踪事物的旋转
You can think about it as you
你可以这样子想象
can only use your hat to view
你只能用你的帽子来观察
virtual content, which also,
虚拟物品 而帽子本身只能
only allows rotation.
通过旋转来观察事物
Meaning you can experience the
也就是说你可以从
virtual content from the same
固定的位置的不同角度
positional point of view, but no
来体验虚拟物体
change in the position is going
但任何位置上的改变都
to be tracked.
无法被跟踪到
The rotation data is tracked
旋转数据是分三个
around three axles.
轴来跟踪
That's why it's also, sometimes,
这也是为什么有的人
called the three degrees of
称它为三个自由度跟踪
You can use it, for example, in
你可以把这个技术应用到一个
a spherical virtual environment.
球形的虚拟环境中
Like, for example, experience a
像体验一个 360 度的视频
360-degree video, in which the
在这个视频中
virtual content can be viewed
体验者可以从同一个位置
from the same positional point.
对虚拟内容进行观察
You can also, use it to augment
也可以用于观察一个距离很远
objects that are very far away.
的 AR 物品上
Orientation Tracking is not
方向跟踪并不适用
suited for physical world
于真实世界中的视觉增强
augmentation, in which you want
因为在真实世界中
to view the content from
你希望能从不同的位置
different points of views.
对事物进行观察
So, let's now have a look at
让我们来看一下
what happens under the hood when
当方向跟踪在运行时
Orientation Tracking is running.
究竟发生了些什么
It is, actually, quite simple.
这很简单
It only uses the rotation data
它只是使用了核心运动
from core motion, which applies
的旋转数据
sensor fusion to the motion
其将传感器融合应用到
sensors data.
运动传感器数据中
As motion data is provided at a
与相机图像相比
higher frequency than the camera
运动数据的更新频率要高出许多
image, Orientation Tracking
一旦相机图像可用
takes the latest motion data
方向跟踪就会
from Core Motion, once the camera
采用这一系列数据中
image is available.
最新的运动数据
And then, returns both results
然后将两个结果
in an ARFrame.
返回给 ARFrame
So, that's it.
就这样
Very simple.
很简单
So, please note that the camera
请注意 在方向跟踪中
feed is not processed in
并不会处理到
Orientation Tracking.
相机回馈信息
Meaning there's no computer
也就是说这个过程
version under the hood here.
中并不会有电脑版本产生
Now, to run Orientation Tracking
如果你想要运转方向跟踪功能
you only need to configure your
你只需要在你的
ARSession with an AROrientation
ARSession 添加
TrackingConfiguration.
AROrientation TrackingConfiguration
The results will then be
所产生的结果将会
returned in an ARCamera object
通过 ARFrame 返回为
provided by the ARFrames.
一个 ARCamera 对象
Now, an ARCamera object always
通常一个 ARCamera 对象
contains the transform, which in
会包括不同的变换
this case of Orientation
在方向跟踪中
Tracking, only contains the
这些变形只包括
rotation data of your tracked
你的现实相机反馈的
physical camera.
旋转数据
Alternatively, the rotation is
这些旋转数据
also represented in eulerAngles.
也可以用欧拉角来代表
You can use whatever fits best
你可以根据自己的喜好来选择
Let's now move over to more
接下来让我们
advanced tracking technologies.
讨论一些更高级的跟踪技术
We'll start with World Tracking.
我们先从世界跟踪开始
World Tracking tracks your
世界跟踪能够跟踪你的
camera viewing orientation, and
相机角度方向
also, the change in position
还能跟踪真实环境中
into your physical environment
的位置变化
without any prior information
而且无需事先了解
about your environment.
你的周围环境
Here, you can see on the left
大家可以看到
side the real camera's view into
左边是现实生活中
the environment, while on the
相机所看到的景象
right side you see the tracked
右边是跟踪相机
camera motion while exploring
在探索过程中的
the world represented in the
跟踪轨迹 这轨迹是用
coordinate system.
坐标系来表示
Let's now explain better, what
接下来 我们将详细
happens here, when World
的说明当世界跟踪运作时
Tracking is running.
到底发生了什么
World Tracking uses a motion
世界跟踪所使用
sensor, the motion data of your
运动传感器
device's accelerometer and
是你设备上的加速器
gyroscope to compute its change
和陀螺仪的运动数据
in orientation and translation
由此高频计算它的方向
on a high frequency.
和旋转变化
It also provides its information
它同时还为 Metal
in correct scale in meters.
提供了正确比例数据
In literature, just this part of
从专业方面来说
the tracking system is also
这一部分的跟踪系统
called Inertial Odometry.
也被称为惯性里程计
While this motion data provides
尽管这一运动数据
good motion information for
能为短间隔动作
movement across small time
提供详细的运动信息
intervals and whenever there's
但当出现
like, sudden movement, it does
突然的运动时
drift over larger time intervals
就可能会出现较长时间的漂移
as the data is not ideally
因为这些数据
precise and subject to
并没有理想中准确
cumulative errors.
而且有累积误差的可能性
That's why it cannot be used
这也是为什么它不能
just by its own for tracking.
单独用于跟踪
Now, to compensate this drift,
为了补偿这一漂移
World Tracking, additionally,
世界跟踪在使用
applies a computer vision
相机图像时
process in which it uses the
应用了一个电脑版本
This technology provides a
这个技术提供了
higher accuracy, but at the cost
更高的准确性 但却
of computation time.
以计算时间为代价
Also, this technology is
同时 它对快速相机运动
sensitive to fast camera motions
十分敏感
and this results in motion blur
这就会导致
in the camera frames.
图像上的模糊
Now, this vision only part of
这一系统中
the system is also called Visual
的版本也被称为
Odometry.
视觉里程计
Now, by fusing those both
通过对计算机视觉和
systems, computer vision and
动作这两个系统的融合
motion, ARKit takes the best of
ARKit 吸收了这两个系统的优势
From computer vision, it takes
ARKit 选用了计算机视觉中
a high accuracy over the larger
长时间间隔的
time intervals.
高准确性
And from the motion data it
而从运动数据中 它吸收了
takes the high update rates and
短时间间隔的准确性
good precision for the smaller
和测量过程中的
time intervals, as well as the
高更新频率以及
metric scale.
以米为测量单位
Now, by combining those both
通过合并这两个系统
systems World Tracking can skip
在处理某些框架时
the computer vision processing
世界跟踪可以跳过
for some of those frames, while
计算机视觉这一步骤
still keeping an efficient and
但仍保持高效和
responsive tracking.
高反馈的跟踪
This frees CPU resources, which
这样子就可以减少 CPU 占用
you can then, additionally, use
你可以将多出的 CPU 空间用于
for your apps.
你的 App 上
In Literature, this combined
在专业方面
technology is also called Visual
这一合并技术也被称为
Inertial Odometry.
视觉惯性里程计
Let's have a closer look at the
让我们进一步了解这一部分
visual part of it.
中的视觉部分
So, within the computer version
计算机视觉正在
process interesting regions in
处理我导出的图像
the camera images are extracted,
中的一个重点区域
like here, the blue and the
像这里的蓝色和橙色的点
And they are extracted such that
它们被提取出来
they can robustly all to be
以确保在同一环境
extracted and other images of
的其他图像中
the same environment.
也能提取出同样的点
Those interesting regions are
这些重点区域
also called features.
也被称为特征
Now, those features are then
可以看到
matched between multiple images
根据它们本身的相似性与外观
over the camera stream based on
可以在同一相机的不同图像中
appearance.
将它们匹配起来
And what then happens is pretty
接下来发生的与你眼睛
much how you are able to see 3D
看到 3D 的效果
with your eyes.
的过程类似
You have two of them and they
这两个点之间
are within the sidewise small
有细微的倾向一侧的距离
And this parallax between the
它们之间的视觉差
eyes is important as this
是十分重要的
results in slightly different
因为它们对环境
views into the environment,
的观察角度有细微的差别
which allows you to see stereo
这个差别能让画面更立体
and perceive the depth.
更有深度感
And this is what ARKit now,
这就是 ARKit 在处理
also, does with the different
三角测量时
views of the same camera stream
对于同一相机
during the process of
不同角度的处理方式
And it does it once there's
只要画面中有足够的视觉差
enough parallax present.
ARKit 就能运行这一功能
It computes the missing depth
它能够计算这些
information for those matched
匹配特征之间的深度数据
Meaning those 2D features from
换句话说 这些图像中的 2D 特征
the image are now reconstructed
通过 3D 方式获得重组
Please, note that this
但是 这个重组
reconstruction to be successful,
成功的关键
the camera position must have
在于相机位置的
changed by a translation to
改变以提供
provide enough parallax.
足够的视觉差
For example, with the sidewise
比如说 往某一侧倾斜的运动
The pure rotation does not give
单纯的旋转并不能为重组
enough information here.
提供足够的信息
So, this is your first small map
这就是有关你所身处环境的
of your environment.
第一份小地图
In ARKit we call this a World
在 ARKit 中 我们将它称为
map.
世界地图
In this same moment, also, the
与此同时 你的镜头的
camera's positions and
相机位置以及
orientations of your sequences
方向都经过了计算
are computed, denoted with a C
在用字母 C 这里标志出来
Meaning, your World Tracking
这代表着你的世界跟踪
just initialized.
刚刚完成初始化
This is the moment of
这是跟踪系统的
system.
初始化阶段
Please note that also in this
当世界地图
moment of this initial
经过初始重组时
reconstruction of the World map,
也定义了
the world origin was defined.
世界原点
And it is set to the first
它被设置为
camera's origin of the
第一个相机的三角框架帧的原点
And it is also set to be gravity
同时也被设置为与重力对齐
It's denoted with a W in the
我们在幻灯片中用 W 来代表
So, you now have a small
因此 你现在可以在
representation of your real
它的世界坐标系
environment reconstructed as a
重建作为世界地图的
World map in its own world
真实环境
coordinates system.
的小型代表
And you have your current camera
你所使用的相机
tracked with respect to the same
也被用同样的
world coordinate system.
世界坐标来跟踪
You can now start adding virtual
现在 你可以往
content to augment them into the
你的相机视角中加入视觉
camera's view.
内容来增强它们
Now, to place virtual content
为了将视觉内容
correctly to an ARSession, you
正确的加入到一个 ARSession 中
should use ARAnchors from ARKit,
你需要运用到 ARkit 中的
which are denoted with an A
ARAnchors 这里我们用
here.
A 来表示
ARAnchors are reference points
ARAnchors 在这个世界地图
within this World map, within
也就是这个世界坐标体系
this world coordinates system.
中是一个参考点
And you should use them because
ARAnchor 是不可或缺的
the World Tracking might update
因为世界跟踪在跟踪
them during the tracking.
时可能会更新
Meaning that, also, all the
也就是说
virtual content that is assigned
所有分配给它的视觉内容都
to it will be updated and
并会被更新并正确
correctly augmented into the
的增强到相机的景象中
camera's view.
既然你已经应用了
ARAnchors you can add virtual
ARAnchors 你可以将视觉内容
content to the anchor, which
添加到锚点中
will them be augmented correctly
这些内容稍后会
into the current camera's view.
以正确的增强方式添加到相机的镜头中
From now on, this created 3D
从现在开始 这个基于你环境的
World map of your environment is
3D 世界地图将会成为
your reference system for the
世界跟踪的参考系统
It is used to reference new
它也是新图像的参考依据
And features are matched from
不同图像中的特征
image to image and triangulated.
互相匹配且进行三角化
And at the same time, also, new
与此同时 新的稳定的
robust features are extracted,
特征被提取出来
matched, and triangulated, which
经过匹配 三角化
are then extending your World
最终能帮助你扩展
map.
你的世界地图
Meaning ARKit is learning your
换句话说 ARKit 正在学习你的环境
This then allows, again, the
这个学习过程会产生
computation of tracking updates
对当前相机的
of the current camera's position
位置和方向的
and orientation.
跟踪计算的更新
And finally, the correct
最后就能向
augmentation into the current
当前相机视角输出
camera's view.
正确的增强元素
While you continue to explore
当你持续不断的探索世界时
the world, World Tracking will
世界跟踪可以
continue to track your physical
持续的跟踪你的相机
camera and continue to learn
并持续学习你
your physical environment.
所处的环境
But over time, the augmentation
但是随着时间的推移
might drift slightly, which can
增强效果可能会出现细微的漂移
be noticed like you can see in
就像你可以在左边
the left image, in a small
的图像中看到
offset of the augmentation.
对增强效果的细微补偿
This is because even small
这是因为就算很细微的补偿
offsets, even small errors will
或者细微的错误
become noticeable when
在经过累积后都
accumulated over time.
会变得明显
Now, when the device comes back
现在这个设备回到了
to a similar view, which was
一个熟悉的视角
already explored before, like
它之前曾经探索过这个视角
for example, the starting point
比如说是我们
where we started the
探索的出发点
exploration, ARKit can perform
ARKit 会进行另外
another optimization step.
一种优化步骤
And this addition makes, a
这一步骤会让
Visual Intertial Odometry
视觉惯性里程计系统
system, makes the system that
这个 ARKit 支持的系统
ARKit supplies to a Visual
转换为一个
Inertial SLAM System.
视觉惯性 SLAM 系统
So, let's bring back this first
现在让我们回到
image where the World Tracking
世界跟踪开始探索
started the exploration.
的第一张图像
So, what happens now is that
世界跟踪现在要做的事情是
World Tracking will check how
检查当前的跟踪信息
well the tracking information
与世界地图对当前
and the World map of the current
景象的渲染是否
view aligns with the past views,
与过去的吻合
like the one from the beginning.
也就是一开始的图像
And will then perform the
接着 ARKit 就会进行
optimization step and align the
优化步骤
current information and the
将当前的信息以及世界地图
current World map with your real
与你的真实
physical environment.
物理环境匹配起来
Have you noticed that during
你们是否有注意到
this step, also the ARAnchor was
在这个过程中
updated?
ARAnchor 也被更新了
And that is the reason why you
这也是为什么你在
should use ARAnchors when adding
往你眼前的景象中加入
virtual content to your
视觉内容时要使用 ARAnchor
In this video, you can see the
在这个视频中 你可以看到
same step again with a real
这个修正步骤在真实相机反馈
camera feed.
中重复了一次
On the left side you see the
在左边 我们可以从相机角度看
environment, and also, features
这个环境 还能看到
which are tracked in the images.
这个图像中所跟踪的特征
And on the right side, you see a
在右边则是
bird eye's view onto the
从俯视角度观察该景象的画面
scenario, showing what ARKit
这代表着 ARKit
knows about it and showing the
了解这个环境并
3D reconstruction of the
正在展示这个环境的 3D 重建
The colors of the points are
这些点的颜色
just encoding the height of the
是根据重建点的高度
reconstructed points with blue
进行编译
being the ground floor and red
蓝色代表地面高度
being the table and the chairs.
红色代表桌子和椅子
Once the camera returns back to
一旦相机回到
a similar view it has seen
它曾经拍摄过的视角
before, like here the starting
就好像这里的开始的视角
point, ARKit will now apply this
ARKit 就会应用
optimization step.
这一优化步骤
So, just pay attention to the
你需要留意的是
point cloud and the camera
点云以及相机轨迹
Have you noticed the update?
不知道你是否有留意到这一更新
Let me show you, once more.
让我再展示一次
This update aligns the ARKit
这个更新将 ARKit
knowledge with your real
的知识与你的现实世界
physical world, and also, the
以及相机运动
camera movement and results in
匹配起来
the better augmentation for the
为接下来的相机帧数
coming camera frames.
提供更好的增强效果
By the way, all those
顺便说一下
computations of World Tracking,
有关世界跟踪的所有计算
and also, all this information
以及有关你所处环境的信息
everything is done on your
这些事情都只需要在你的设备
device only.
上就可以完成
And all this information, also,
这些数据也只存在于
stays on your device only.
你的设备上
So, how can you use this complex
如何才能将这一复杂的
technology, now, in your app?
技术应用到你的 App 中呢
It is actually quite simple.
很简单
To run World Tracking you just
如果你想要运行世界跟踪功能
configure your ARSession with an
你只需要在你的 ARSession 中
ARWorldTrackingConfiguration.
添加 ARWorldTrackingConfiguration 类
Again, its results are returned
它将会以 ARCamera
in an ARCamera object of the
的对象 ARFrame 形式返回结果
An ARCamera object, again,
ARCamera 的对象
contains the transform, which in
包括了转换
this case of World Tracking
在世界跟踪中
contains, additionally, to the
转换还包括旋转
rotation, also, the translation
以及对跟踪相机的平移
Additionally, the ARCamera also
除此之外 ARCamera 还包括
contains information about the
有关跟踪状态
tracking state and
以及 trackingStateReason
trackingStateReason.
的信息
This will provide some
这将会为当前
information about the current
的跟踪质量提供
tracking quality.
一些信息
So, tracking quality.
接下来 要讨论的是跟踪质量
Have you ever experienced
你是否曾经使用过一个
opening an AR app and the
跟踪十分差劲
tracking worked very poorly or
或者根本不能跟踪
maybe it didn't work at all?
的 AR App 呢
How did that feel?
那时你的感觉是怎么样的
Maybe frustrating?
是不是很崩溃
You might not open the app,
可能你再也不会用
again.
这个 App 了
So, how can you get a higher
那么 怎样才在你的 App 中
tracking quality for your app?
实现更好的跟踪质量呢
For this, we need to understand
要实现更好的跟踪质量
the main factors that are
我们需要明白什么主要因素
influencing the tracking
会影响到跟踪质量
And I want to highlight three of
在这里 我想要强调其中三点
First of all, World Tracking
首先 世界跟踪依赖于
relies on a constant stream of
持续不断的
camera images and sensor data.
相机图像以及传感器数据
If this is interrupted for too
如果这些信息中断太久
long, tracking will become
就可能会限制跟踪
Second, World Tracking also
第二 世界跟踪在
works best in textured and
纹理明显 光线充足的环境下
well-lit environments because
才最好的工作
World Tracking uses those
因为世界跟踪需要用到
visually robust points to map
这些特征点来作为参考
and finally triangulate its
并最终将其位置三角化
It is important that there is
所以环境需要有
enough visual complexity in the
足够的视觉复杂性这一点
environment.
是十分重要的
If this is not the case because
如果环境达不到这一要求
it's, for example, too dark or
比如说光线过于昏暗
you're looking against a white
或者你正对着一面白墙
wall, then also, the tracking
那跟踪的表现
will perform poorly.
就会很糟糕
And third, also, World Tracking
第三点是世界跟踪的
works best in static
最佳运作环境
environments.
是静态环境
If too much of what your camera
如果你的取景框中
sees is moving, then the visual
大部分事物都是移动的
data won't correspond with the
那就会导致视觉数据与
motion data, which might result
运动数据不吻合
in the potential drift.
最终可能会导致漂移
Also, device itself should not
同时 设备不能处于
be on a moving platform like a
一个移动平台上
bus or an elevator.
比如说公交车或者电梯
Because in those moments the
假设设备被放置在电梯之中
motion sensor would actually
那运动传感器
sense a motion like going up or
会检测到
down in the elevator while,
向上或向下的运动趋势
visually, your environment had
但视觉上 它所处的环境
not changed.
并没有变化
So, how can you get notified
那你要如何获得
about the tracking quality that
用户在使用
the user is currently
你的 App 时的体验的反馈呢
ARKit monitors its tracking
ARKit 会监控它自己的跟踪表现
We applied machine learning,
我们在 ARKit 中应用了机器学习
which was trained on thousands
ARKit 在成千上万组
of data sets to which we had the
的数据学习中获得提升
information how well tracking
这些数据中包括在不同
performed in those situations.
情况下跟踪的表现
To train a classifier, which
为了训练出一个能够
tells you how tracking performs,
告诉你跟踪表现的分类器
we used annotations like the
我们使用了一些注释
number of visual-- visible
比如视觉内容的数量
features tracked in the image
在图像中跟踪到的可视特征
and also, the current velocity
以及设备当时的运动速率
Now, during runtime, the health
在运作时 跟踪的表现
of tracking is determined based
是由这些参数
on those parameters.
所决定的
In this video, we can see how
在这段视频中
the health estimate, which can
我们将镜头遮住
be seen-- which, is reported in
但保持活动和
the lower left, gets worse when
对环境的探索
the camera is covered while we
可以看到左下角的健康预估
are still moving and exploring
指数在下降
It also shows how it returns
而当我们把遮住镜头
back to normal after the camera
的东西移走时
view is uncovered.
这一数据就回归正常
Now, ARKit simplifies its
ARKit 通过给用户
information for you by providing
提供一个跟踪状态将
a tracking state.
数据进行简化
And the tracking state can have
跟踪状态由三个
three different values.
不同的值表示
It can be normal, which is the
正常也就是
healthy state and is the case in
健康状态 大部分情况下
most of the time.
都是这种状态
It's the case in most of the
没错 在大部分情况下都会是这种状态
And it can also be limited,
另一种状态是限制状态
which is whenever tracking
这种状态会出现在跟踪
performs poorly.
表现糟糕时
If that's the case, then the
如果出现了这种状态
limited state will also come
那 ARKit 还会告诉你限制
along with the reason, like
的原因 比如说没有足够的
insufficient features or
特征或者
excessive motion or being
移动太快或者
currently in the initialization
当前正处于初始化阶段
It can also be not available,
还有另一种状态便是不可用状态
which means that tracking did
这意味着当前还未
not start yet.
完成初始化
Now, whenever the tracking state
这样子 不管跟踪状态何时改变
changes, a delegate is called.
你都能够知道
The camera did change tracking
相机在跟踪过程中确实
state.
会发生变化
And this gives you the
这个功能让你能够
opportunity to notify the user
在限制状态出现时
when a limited state has been
及时地通知
encountered.
你的用户
You should, then, give
你还需要为你的
informative and actionable
用户提供有关
feedback what the user can do to
改善他们跟踪情况
improve his tracking situation,
的高实用性且可操作的建议
as most of it is actually in the
因为改进跟踪环境的主动权
user's hand.
掌握在用户手上
Like for example, as we learned
这些建议可以是
before, like a sidewise movement
我们之前讨论过的 往某侧移动以
to allow initialization or
运行设备进行初始化
making sure there's enough
或者确保有足够的
adequate lighting for enough
光线来保证
visual complexity.
足够的复杂性
So, let me wrap up the World
接下来 我将会总结一下
Tracking for you.
世界跟踪
World Tracking tracks your
世界跟踪为你的相机
camera 6 degree of freedom
提供方向和位置的 6
orientation and position with
自由度跟踪
respect to your surrounding
这个跟踪基于你所处的环境
environment and without any
但它本身对你所处
prior information about your
对环境并没有
environment, which then allows
事先的了解
the physical world augmentation
这个跟踪让在真实
in which the content can
世界中的增强内容
actually be viewed from any kind
可以从任何角度进行察看
Also, World Tracking creates a
世界跟踪也创造了一个
World map, which becomes the
世界地图
tracking's reference system to
这个世界地图成为
localize new camera images
新的图像定位的参考系统
To create a great user
为了提供更好的用户体验
experience, the tracking quality
跟踪质量需要被监控
should be monitored and feedback
并能为用户提供
and guidance should be provided
反馈或者指引
And World Tracking runs on your
世界跟踪只在你的
device only.
设备上运行
And all results stay on your
所有的结果都只保存
device.
于你的设备中
If you have not done it already,
如果你还没有尝试过这个
try out one of our developer
不妨在我们的开发者
examples.
模板中试一下
For example, the Build Your
比如说你可以创造你的
First AR Experience, and play a
AR 初体验
bit around, just 15 minutes with
你可以做出一些探索
the tracking quality in
花上 15 分钟时间了解不同情况
different situations; light
下的跟踪质量 比如不同灯光效果
situations or movements.
或者运动频率
And always remember to guide the
一直记住 在用户遇到
user whenever he encounters a
限制跟踪状态时
limited tracking situation to
要及时给他提供指导
guarantee that he has a great
以保证他能有一个
tracking experience.
好的跟踪体验
So, World Tracking is about the
世界跟踪与相机相关
camera-- where your camera is
它与你的相机位置
with respect to your physical
以及你所处的环境相关
Let's now talk about how the
接下来 我们要讨论
virtual content can interact
视觉内容是如何
with the physical environment.
与现实环境互动的
And this is possible with Plane
这一效果时通过平面检测
Detection.
来实现
The following video, again, from
接下来这段视频
the Ikea app, shows a great use
没错这段视频也来自于 Ikea App
case for the Plane Detection,
是一个很棒的平面检测例子
placing virtual objects into
将虚拟物品放置到
your physical environment, and
你的真实环境中
then interacting with it.
并与它互动
So first, please note how, also,
首先 我们要留意的是
in the Ikea app the user is
在 Ikea App 中 设计者是如何
guided to make some movement.
指引用户进行运动的
Then, once a horizontal plane is
接着 一旦检测到水平面后
detected, the virtual table set
一个虚拟桌子出现
is displayed and is waiting to
并等待着你去放置
Once you position it, rotate it
你为它选好位置 并按照你的
as you want it, you can lock the
想法旋转后
object in its environment.
你可以将它固定到环境中
And did you notice the
你是否有留意到
interaction between the detected
当你将这个桌子固定住时
ground plane and the table set
平面与桌子之间的互动
It kind of bounces shortly on
就是地面有轻微的抖动
And this is possible because we
当我们知道地面在哪时
know where the ground plane is.
我们就可以实现这个效果
So, let's have a look at what
让我们进一步的讨论
happened under the hood here.
这个过程中究竟发生了什么
Plane Detection uses the World
平面检测所运用的
map provided by the world I just
是我刚刚所提到的
talked about, just talked about
世界地图
a moment ago, which is
在这里我们用
represented here in those yellow
黄色的点来代表它
And then, it uses them to detect
平面检测利用这些点
surfaces that are horizontal or
来检测水平或者垂直的平面
vertical, like the ground, the
比如说地面
bench, and the small wall.
长椅以及小墙面
It does this by accumulating
它通过积累多个
information over multiple
ARFrame 的信息
ARFrames.
来实现这个效果
So, as the user moves around the
随着用户对场景的
scene, more and more information
进一步探索 它能获得
about the real surface is
更多有关真实平面的信息
It also allows the Plane
这些信息让平面检测
Detection to provide and like
可以提供和扩张平面
convex hull.
就像一个凸壳
If multiple planes belonging to
如果在同一物理表面上
the same physical surface are
检测到多于一个的平面
detected, like in this part now,
就像我们现在看的这一部分
the green and the purple one,
绿色和紫色的平面
then they will be merged once
一旦他们重叠到一起
they start overlapping.
就会被合并
If horizontal and vertical
如果水平和垂直的平面
planes intersect they are
出现相交的情况
clipped at the line of
它们相交的地方会被剪掉
a new feature in ARKit 2.
这也是 ARKit 2 中的新功能
Plane Detection is designed to
平面检测被设定为
have very little overhead as it
有很少的误差
repurposes the mapped 3D points
因为它重新使用了世界跟踪
from the World Tracking.
中的 3D 点
And then it fits planes into
然后它将平面放置到
those point clouds and over time
这些点云中
continuously aggregates more and
并不断的集合越来越多的点
more points and merge the planes
将已重叠的平面
that start to overlap.
合并起来
Therefore, it takes some time
所以 检测第一个平面
until the first planes are
需要耗费一定的时间
What does that mean for you?
这对你有什么影响呢
If your app is started, there
当你的 App 刚启动时
might not directly be planes to
可能并不会立刻有可以
place objects on or to interact
放置物品或与物品互动的平面
If the detection of a plane is
如果你的体验一定需要
mandatory for your experience,
检测到平面的话
you should again guide the user
你需要指引你的用户
to move the camera with enough
移动相机以获得足够
translation to ensure a dense
的平移来提供
reconstruction based on the
足够的视觉差以保证密集的重建
parallax, and also, enough
以及在场景中
visual complexity in the scene.
有足够的视觉复杂性
Again, for the reconstruction, a
对了 单有旋转数据是
rotation only is not enough.
不足以重建的
Now, how can you enable the
怎么样才能启用
Plane Detection?
平面检测呢
It's, again, very simple.
这个也很简单
As the Plane Detection reuses
因为平面检测使用的是
the 3D map from the World
世界跟踪的 3D 地图
Tracking, it can be configured
它可以通过使用
by using the
ARWorldTrackingConfiguration
ARWorldTrackingConfiguration.
这一参数进行配置
Then, the property
planeDetection 的特征
planeDetection just needs to be
可以设置为
set to either horizontal,
水平 垂直
vertical, or like in this case,
或者像这种情况下
both.
两者皆可
And then, just call your
接下来你便可以
ARSession with this
用这个配置
configuration.
来运行你的 ARSession
And the detection of the planes
ARKit 就开始对
will be started.
平面的检测了
Now, how are those, the results
那这些检测到的平面结果
of the detected planes returned
是如何返回给你的呢
The detected planes are returned
检测的平面会以
as an ARPlaneAnchor.
ARPlaneAnchor 的形式返回给你
An ARPlaneAnchor is a subclass
ARPlaneAnchor 是 ARAnchor
of an ARAnchor.
的一个子类
Each ARAnchor provides a
每个 ARAnchor 都会提供一个变换
information where the anchor is
这个变换包含锚点在你
in your World map.
的世界地图中的位置信息
Now, a plane anchor,
一个平面锚点
specifically, also has
也有着有关平面表面的几何信息
which is represented in two
这些信息有两种
alternative ways.
可选的代表方式
Either like a bounding box with
一种是像一个有着中心点
a center and an extent, or as a
和拓展的密封箱子
3D mesh describing the shape of
另一种则是 3D 网格
the convex hull of the detected
这些网格描述着
plane and its geometry property.
所检测到的平面的凸壳以及其几何特征
To get notified about detected
当平面出现增加 更新
planes, delegates are going to
或者移除的情况时
be called whenever planes are
需要有提示
added, updated, or removed.
来通知我们
This will then allow you to use
这能让你及时
those planes, as well as react
利用这些平面并对更新
to any updates.
做出反应
Now, what can you do with
你可以对平面做些什么呢
Like what we've seen before on
我们刚刚在 Ikea App 中
the Ikea app, these are great
看到的就是很好的例子
Place virtual objects, for
比如说你可以通过冲击测试
example, with hit testing.
来放置虚拟物品
Or you can interact with some,
你也可以与一些
for example, physically.
虚拟物品进行真实互动
Like we've seen bouncing is a
就好像我们刚刚也看到了
possibility.
抖动是可以实现的
Or you can also use it by adding
你也可以在检测到的平面
an occlusion plane into the
上添加一个遮挡平面
detected plane, which will then
所有虚拟物品
hide all the virtual content
就会被隐藏到
below or behind the added
这个遮挡屏幕之下或者之后
So, let me summarize what we've
所以 让我来总结一下我们现在
already gone through.
所学习了的东西
We've had a look at the
我们了解了方向跟踪
Orientation Tracking, the World
世界跟踪
Tracking, and the Plane
以及平面检测
Next, Michele will explain, in
接下里 Michele 将会
depth, our new tracking
进一步的介绍我们的新的
technologies, which were
跟踪技术 这些技术
introduced in ARKit 2.
将会应用在 ARKit 2 中
So, welcome Michele.
让我们欢迎 Michele
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Marion.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Marion
My name is Michele, and it's a
大家好 我是 Michele
pleasure to continue with the
很高兴能负责为大家
remaining topics of this
讲解此次演示
session.
余下的话题
Next up is saving and loading
接下来要讨论的是保存和
maps.
加载地图
This is a feature that allows to
这个功能可以
store all the information that
将一个阶段中所需要的
are required in a session.
所有数据存储起来
So, that it can literally be
这样子 在稍后的另一个阶段中
restored in another session at a
这些数据就可以
later point in time to create
被重新运用并用于
augmented reality experiences
创造与某个特定地区
that persist to a particular
体验一致的 AR 体验
Or that could, also, be stored
或者它也可以存储在
by another device to create
另一个设备上来创造
multiple user augmented reality
多用户的 AR 体验
Let's take a look at an example.
举个例子
What you see here is a guy;
这里有个男人
let's name him Andre, that's
让我们叫他 Andre
walking around the table with
他手里拿着设备
his device having an augmented
绕着桌子走
reality experience.
正在体验 AR
And you can see his device now
你可以看到他现在
is making this seem more
通过手上的设备往桌上
interesting by adding a virtual
添加了一个虚拟花瓶
vase on the table.
让这一切看起来更有趣了
A few minutes later his friends
几分钟后
arrive at the same scene.
他的朋友也来了
And now, they're both looking at
现在他们都看着这个场景
You're going to see Andre's
Andre 的设备在左边
device on the left and his
而他朋友的设备
friend on the right now.
在右边
So, you can see that they're
你可以看到他们
looking at the same space.
正在看同一个空间
They can see each other.
他们能看到彼此
But most importantly, they see
但最重要的是
the same virtual content.
他们可以看到同样的虚拟内容
They're having a shared
他们正在体验的是一个
augmented reality experience.
共享的 AR 体验
So, what we have seen in these
上面这个例子
examples can be discovered in
可以被分为三个阶段
First, Andre went around the
第一个阶段 Andre 围着
table and acquired the World
桌子走动并获得了世界地图
Then, the World map was shared
第二个阶段 世界地图在设备之间
across devices.
进行了分享
And then, his friend's device
第三个阶段 他的朋友的设备
re-localized to the World map.
重新定位了世界地图
This means that ARKit was
这意味着这个对象
able to understand in the new
在新设备上也能识别
device that this was the same
这个场景与另一个设备上的是相同的
computed the precise position of
然后根据地图来
the device with respect to the
计算设备的准确位置
map, and then, started tracking
之后就开始跟踪
from there just like the new
就好像新加入的设备
device acquired the World map
自己获取了这个世界地图一样
We're going to go into more
接下来 我们将会对
detail about these three phases.
这三个阶段进行更细节的了解
But first, let's review what's
但首先 让我们复习一下
in the World map.
什么是世界地图
The World map includes all the
世界地图包括
tracking data that are needed
系统定位所需要的
for the system to be localized,
所有跟踪数据
which includes the feature
包括那些特征点
points as Marion greatly
就像 Marion 刚刚已经
explained before.
详细解释的一样
As well as local appearance for
也包括了这个点的
this point.
周围外观
They also contain all the
世界地图还包括了
anchors that were added to the
被添加到环节中的
session, either by the users,
所有锚点 不管这些锚点是由用户
like planes, for example.
添加的 比如说像平面
I mean by the system-- like
我的意思是像由系统
planes.
添加的平面
Or by the users, like the vase,
或者由用户添加的锚点
as we have seen in the example.
就像我们刚刚在示范中看到的花瓶
This data is serializable and
这个数据是可串性化
available to you so that you can
可获取的 你可以利用这些数据
create compelling persistent or
来创造一些可持续的
multiple user augmented reality
或者多用户的 AR 体验
So, now let's take a look at the
现在让我们来看看第一个阶段
first stage, which is acquiring
也就是获得
the World map.
世界地图的阶段
We can play back the first video
我们可以回放第一段视频
where Andre went around the
Andre 绕着桌子走到时候
table that you can see his
在左边 你可以
device on the left, here.
看到他的设备 就在这里
And on the right, you see the
在右边 你可以以鸟瞰角度
World map from a top view as
看到通过跟踪系统获得
acquired by the tracking system.
的世界地图
You can recognize the circle is the table
你可以围绕着
and the chair around it.
它的桌子和椅子
There's a few things to pay
在这个获取过程中
attention to during this
有几点需要我们注意
First, everything that Marion
首先 Marion 在跟踪部分
said during tracking also
所说到的所有技术 都在这里得到应用
So, we want enough visual
场景需要有足够的
complexity on the scene to get
视觉复杂性
dense feature points on the map.
地图才能获得足够的深度特征点
And the scene must be static.
场景需要是静止的 当然
Of course, we can deal with
如果有细微的变化
minor changes, as you have seen
也是没有关系的
the tablecloth moving by the
大家也可以看到桌布被风吹动
But the scene must be mostly
但场景的主要部分
static.
需要是静止的
In addition, when we are
另外 在我们
specifically acquiring a World
获取世界地图进行分享时
map for sharing we want to go
我们需要从多个
around the environment from
不同的角度来
multiple points of view.
探索这个环境
In particular, we want to cover
特别是我们想要
all the direction from which we
覆盖所有我们想要
want to later be localized from.
被定位的方向
To make this easy, we also made
为了让这个过程变得更简单
available a world mapping status
我们增加了世界地图状态提示
which gives you information
让你能了解有关
about the World map.
世界地图的信息
If you guys have been to the
如果你们有参加过
What's New in ARKit talk,
What's New in ARKit 这一演讲
Arsalan greatly expand this
那么 Arsalan 会极大的扩展这一点
to quickly recap.
以便快速回顾一下
When you start the session the
当你开始会话时
World map status will start
世界地图的状态 会从限制状态开始
limited.
随着设备了解了
extending as more of the scene is
更多场景的信息
learned by the device.
就会变成初始化的状态
And then, finally, we go to
最后当系统
mapped when the system is
确定你保持在同一位置时
confident you're staying in the
我们终于可以开始
same place.
绘制地图了
And that's when you want to save
这是在制图阶段
the map in the mapped state.
你想要保存的地图
So, that's good information.
所以 这是好的信息
But this is mostly on the user
但是这主要是
side applied to acquire the
用户方面的适用操作
So, what does this mean to you
所以 这对开发者而言
as a developer?
代表着什么呢
That you need to guide the user.
意味着你需要给用户提供指引
So, we can indicate the mapping
我们可以告知用户制图时
status and even disabling the
的不同状态
saving or sharing of the World
甚至可以设置不允许保存
map until the mapping status
或者分享世界地图
goes to the mapped state.
直到制图状态显示绘制状态
We can also, monitor the
我们也可以监控在
tracking quality during the
获取环节中的
acquisition session and report
跟踪质量
to the user if the tracking
如果跟踪状态出现一段时间的
state has been limited for more
限制状态 比如说持续几秒
than a few seconds.
就可以反馈给用户
And maybe even give an option to
或许甚至可以提供
restart the acquisition session.
重新开始获取环节的选项
On the receiving end of the
在设备的接受方面
device, we can also guide the
我们也可以指引用户
user to better localization
以获得更好的定位流程
So, when we are, again, in the
我们又回到了获取设备这里
acquisition device, when we are
当我们在地图阶段时
in the map state we can take a
我们可以对场景进行拍照
picture of the scene and then,
然后将它与
ship that together with the
世界地图一起发出
World map.
在接收端
ask the user find this view to
我们可以让用户找到这个视觉
start your shared experience.
来开始你的分享体验
That was how to acquire the
这就是获得
World map.
世界地图的流程
Now, let's see how you can share
现在 让我们了解一下如何
the World map.
才能分享世界地图
First, you can get the World map
首先 你可以简单地通过
by simply calling the
在 ARSession 中运行
getCurrentWorldMap method in the
getCurrentWorldMap 方式来
ARSession.
获得世界地图
And this will give you the World
这是获得世界地图的一种方式
The World map is a serializable
世界地图是一个可串行化的类
class.
所以我们可以通过
NSKeyedArchiver utility to
NSKeyedArchiver 公式来
serialize it to a binary stream
将它串行为一串二进制的数据
of data, which then, you can
你可以选择将这串数据
either save to disk in case of a
保存在硬盘中
single user persistent
供单机持续性的应用
Or you can share it across
你也可以选择 将它在设备之间分享
And for that, you can use the
为了实现设备间分享
MultiPeerConnectivity framework,
你可以使用 MultiPeerConnectivity 框架
which has great feature like
这个框架有着很棒的功能
automatic device, nearby device
像自动装置 发现附近设备等
discovery, and allows efficient
这使设备之间的数据
communication of data between
可以高效沟通
We also, have an example of how
我们在 ARKit 中也有如何运用
to use that in ARKit called
这个技巧的例子
Creating a Multiuser AR
被称为 创造一个多用户的
Experience that you can check
AR 体验
out on our developer website.
你可以在我们的开发者网站上找到这个例子
On the receiving end of the
让我们看一下
device, once you've got the
接收端设备一旦收到世界地图之后
World map let's see how you can
需要如何设置
set up the World Tracking
世界跟踪参数
configuration to use it.
来使用这个地图
Very simple.
非常简单
You just set the initial World
你只需要赋予世界地图
map property to that World map.
原始数据地图的特征
When you run the session, the
当你运行这个会话时
system will try to find that
系统会尝试去寻找
previous World map.
之前的世界地图
But it may take some time, even
但这会耗费一定时间
because the user may not be
因为用户可能并没有
pointing at the same scene as
从以前的位置拍摄
before.
这一的场景
So, how do we know when
那我们怎样才能知道
localization happen?
定位正在运行呢
That information is available in
这个信息可以在跟踪阶段获得
So, as soon as you start the
只要你用原始世界地图
session with the initial World
开始一个会话
map, the tracking state will be
那跟踪阶段就会被
limited with reason
限制为重新定位
Note that you will still get the
但在这里你还是可以获得
tracking data available here,
跟踪数据
but the world origin will be the
但原始世界将会是
first camera, just like a new
第一个相机 就像在一个新的会话中一样
As soon as the user points the
只要用户将设备
device to the same scene, the
对着同样的场景时
system will localize.
系统就会开始定位
The tracking state will go to
跟踪阶段会重归正常
normal and the world origin will
同时原始世界
be the same as the recorded
将会与记录的世界地图一致
At this point, all your previous
在这里 你之前的所有
anchors are also available in
锚点在你的会话中
your session, so you can put
都是可用的 所以你可以将以前
back the virtual content.
的虚拟内容放回来
Note here that because of what's
在这里需要留意的是
happening behind the hood,
这些幕后操作
behind the scenes, is that we're
是我们
matching those feature points,
正在匹配那些特征点
there needs to be enough visual
你获得世界地图的场景
similarity between the scenes
与你想要重新定位的
where you acquired the World map
场景之间需要有
and the scene where you want to
足够的视觉相似性
So, if you go back to this table
所以 如果你想在晚上的时候
at night, chances are it's not
回到这个桌子旁进行 AR 体验
going to work very well.
那效果很可能会不好
And that was how you can create
这就是你如何通过
multiple user experiences or
保存或者加载地图
persistent experiences using the
来实现多用户体验
saving and loading map.
或者持续体验的方式
Next, image tracking.
接下来要讲的是图像跟踪
So, augmented reality is all
AR 就是
about adding visual content on
在物理世界上添加
top of the physical world.
一些虚拟内容
And on the physical world,
在物理世界中
images are found everywhere.
到处都可以发现图像
Think about art pieces, pieces of art hanging on the wall the
想想
world, magazine covers,
杂志封面
advertisements.
广告
Image tracking is a tool that
图像跟踪是一个工具
allows you to recognize those
它让你能识别这些真实图像
physical images and build
并能在他们的周围
augmented reality experiences
建立 AR 体验
Let's see an example.
让我们来看一个例子
You can see here; two images
大家可以看到这里
being tracked simultaneously.
有两张图像被同时跟踪
On the left, a beautiful
在左边的图像中
elephant is put on top of the
一只美丽的大象被
physical image of the elephant.
放在真实图像中的大象之上
On the right, the physical image
而在右边 一个真实的图像
turned into a virtual screen.
被转化为一个虚拟的屏幕
Note also, that the images can
还有一点需要留意的
freely move around the
图像可以在环境中随意移动
environment as tracking around
因为相机正在以每秒 60 帧的
at 60 frames per second.
速度进行跟踪
Let's talk about looking at
接下来让我们
what's happening behind the
讨论在这景象
scenes.
背后发生了些什么
So, let's say you have an image
假设说你有一张
like this one of the elephant
和这个大象一样的图像
and you want to find it in a
你想要在一个类似这样的
scene like this.
景象中找到它
We're using grayscale for this.
我们将会用灰度来实现这个效果
And the first type is pretty
第一种方式
similar to what we do in
和我们在跟踪时用到的
tracking.
有点类似
So, we'll track those
我们会跟踪
interesting points from both the
参考图像与
reference image and the current
当前环境中的特征点
And then, we try to go in the
然后 我们会试图
current scene and match those
在当前的场景中匹配
features to the one on the
那些在参考图像中特征点
By applying some projected
通过运用一些投影几何
geometry and linear algebra,
以及线性代数
this is enough to give an
这就可以根据
initial estimation of the
当前的场景
position orientation of the
对图像的位置方向
image with respect to the
进行初步的估算
But we don't stop here.
但我们并不满足于此
In order to give you a really
为了让你能获得一个
precise pose and track at 60
真正准确的姿势并做到
frames per second, we then do a
每秒 60 帧的跟踪
dense tracking stage.
我们做了一个高密度跟踪阶段
So, with that initial estimate
在初步的预估之后
we take the pixels from the
所以我们将现有场景的像素
current scene and warp them back
回溯到一个
to a rectangular shape like you
长方形的形状
see on the right-- top right
也就是你在右边 右上角所能看到的
So, that's a reconstructed image
所以这是将
by warping the pixels of the
现有图像的像素回溯成
current image into the
一个长方形后重组的图像
We can then compare the
我们将重组后的图像
reconstructed image with a
与我们所拥有的
reference image that we have
参考图像进行对比
available to create an error
来创造你们所看到的
image like the one you see
下面这个误差图像
We then optimize the position
接下来 我们会优化图像的位置方向
that that error is minimized.
这样能使误差最小化
So, what this means to you that
这也意味着
the pose would be really
对你来说这个结果将会
accurate.
十分准确
Thank you.
谢谢
And will still track at 60
而且还能做到每秒
frames per second.
跟踪 60 帧
So, let's see how we can do all
让我们看看我们在
of this in ARKit.
ARKit 中时如何实现这些
As usual, the ARKit API is
照常 ARKit 的 API
really simple.
十分简单
We have three simple steps.
我们只需要做三个简单的步骤
First, we want to collect all
首先 我们需要收集
the reference images.
所有参考图像
Then, we set up the AR Session
接着 我们要设置 AR 会话的参数
There are two options here.
我们有两种选择
One is the World Tracking
一个是世界跟踪配置
configuration that gives, also,
它也提供设备位置
And this is the one we have
这个是我们目前所讨论的方式
And in iOS12, introduced a new
在 iOS 12 中 将会有一个新的配置
standalone image tracking
这是一个独立的跟踪配置
Once you start the session you
一旦你开始了会话
will start receiving the results
你就会开始通过 ARImageAnchor
in the form of an ARImageAnchor.
的形式接收结果
We're now going into more
下面 我们将会
details of these three steps,
进一步研究这三个步骤
starting from the reference
让我们从参考图像开始
The easiest way to add reference
往你的 App 中加入
images to your application is
参考图像的最便捷方式
through the, Xcode asset
就是通过资产目录
You simply create an AR Resource
你可以创造一个 AR 资源组
Groups and drag and drop your
然后将你的图像拖拽到组里
Next, you have to set the
接下来 你需要设置
physical dimension of the image,
图像的物理尺寸
which you can do on the property
你可以通过右上角
window on the top right.
的特征窗口进行设置
Setting the physical dimension
设置物理尺寸是硬性要求
is a requirement and there's a
这里有几个原因
First, it allows the pose of the
第一 设置物理尺寸能让
image to be in physical scale.
图像以物理尺寸展示
Which means, also, your content
也就是说 你的内容
will be in physical scale.
将会是物理大小
In ARKit, everything is in
在 ARKit 中 所有事物都是
meters, so also, your visual
以米为测量单位 所以你的虚拟
content will be in meters.
物品将会以米为长度
In addition, it's especially
第二 设置正确的
important to set the correct
图像物理尺寸是十分重要的
physical dimension of the image
因为我们
in case we combine the image
有可能会将图像跟踪
tracking with the World
与世界跟踪合并到一起
As this will give immediately
这会立刻给予图像
consistent pose between the
与世界之间
image and the world.
一致的姿态
Let's see some example of this
让我们看看有关参考图像的
reference images.
更多例子
You can see here, two beautiful
这里有两幅很漂亮的图像
These images will work really
这些图像十分适合
great with image tracking.
图像跟踪
They have high texture, high
它们有着高饱和度
level of contrast, well
高对比度
distributed histograms, as well
合理分配的柱形图
as they do not contain
并且没有重复的结构
There are, also, other kinds of
这里也有一些
images that will work less good
和系统适配度不高的图像
You can see an example of this
右边这个图像就是不合适类型
on the right.
的一个示范
And if we take a look at these
如果我们仔细观察上面
top two examples, you can see
这两个例子 我们会发现
that the good image we have a
好的图像都有着
lot of those interesting points.
许多关键点
And you can see that the
图像中的
histogram is well distributed
柱形图在整个
across the whole range.
范围内平均分布
While on the Snow image,
而右边的图像
there's only a few of those
则只有很少的关键点
interesting points and the
它们的柱形图也
histogram is all skewed toward
倾向白色的部分
You can get an estimation of how
在 Xcode 中
good an image will be directly
你可以直观的了解到一张图像
in Xcode.
是否适合用于跟踪
As soon as you drag an image in
你只需要将图像拖放到
there, the image is analyzed and
Xcode 中 Xcode 就会自动
problems are reported to you in the form
对图像进行分析 然后界面会以
of warnings to give you early
警告的方式给你及早的反馈
feedback, even before you run
这个反馈甚至还要早于你 运行你的 App
For example, if you click on
比如说 如果你点击
this bottom image that could be
底部的这张图像
a magazine page, for example, we
这张图像可能是杂志的某一页
can see that the Xcode says that
我们可以看到 Xcode 反馈说
the histogram is not well
这张图像的柱形图 分布不均匀
In fact, you can see there's a
你可以看到图像中
lot of whites in the image.
有大量的白色
And it would also say that this
这个图像也包含了许多重复结构
structures, mainly caused by the
这些重复结构主要是文字
text.
另一个例子就是 如果你有两张
images which are too similar and
极其类似且
are at risk of being confused at
十分容易在检测时混淆的图像
detection time, also, Xcode
Xcode 也会
warns you about that.
做出相应的警告
You can see an example of these
这两张有关
two images of the same mountain
同一齿状山脉的图像
range, the Sierra.
就是一个很好的例子
There's a few things that we can
如果这个警告出现时
do to deal with this warning.
我们并不能做什么来改正
For example, let's go back to
例如 让我们回到这张
this image that had repetitive
有着重复结构
structures and not well
且分布不平均
distributed histograms.
的柱形图图像
You can try to identify a region
你可以尝试去定位
of this image which is
这张图像中区别足够
distinctive enough, like in this
明显的地方 在这里
case, for example, the actual
就是页面中真正的
image of the page.
图像部分
And then, you can crop that out
接下来 你就可以对图像
and use this as the reference
进行裁剪 将裁剪后的图像
image, instead.
作为参考图像
Which will give you, of course,
这样子 Xcode 就不会发出
all the warnings are going to be
任何警告
removed and will give you better
你也可以获得更好的
tracking quality.
跟踪质量
Another thing that we can do is
我们还可以
use multiple AR Resource Groups.
使用多个 AR 资源群组
This allow many more images to
这个功能可以同时检测
be detected.
多张图像
As we recommend to have a
为了保持体验的高效性
maximum of 25 images per group
与反应性
to keep your experience
你可以设置每个组最多
efficient and responsive.
只能处理 25 张图像
But you can have as many groups
但群组的数量
as you want.
是没有限制的
And then, you can switch between
接着 你就可以通过编程
groups programmatically.
的方式切换不同的群组
For example, if you are want to
举个例子 如果你想要创造
create an augmented reality
一个博物馆中的 AR 体验
experience in a museum that may
这个博物馆可能有着
have hundreds of images.
成千上百的图像
Usually though, those images are
通常 这些图像
actually physically located in
分布在博物馆的
different rooms.
不同房间中
So, what you can do is put the
那你将要做的是
images that physically will be
将在同一个房间中的图像
present in the room into a
划分到一个群组中
And images of another room into
在另外一个房间的图像则属于
another group.
另一个群组
And then use, for example, core
随后 你可以用中心定点
location to switch between
来切换不同的房间
Note also, that you can have
在这种情况下
similar images, now, as long as
只要在不同的群组中就可以
they are in different groups.
存在类似的图像
So, that was all about reference
好的 以上就是有关
images.
参考图像的信息
Let's now, see our two
现在 让我们来看看我们的两个配置吧
The ARImageTrackingConfiguration
ARImageTrackingConfiguration
is a new standalone image
是一个全新的 独立的
tracking configuration, which
图像跟踪配置
means it doesn't run the World
这意味着它不会运转世界跟踪
Which also, means there is no
也就是说并没有
world origin.
它并没有世界原点
So, every image will be given to
所以 每一张反馈给你的图像
you with respect to the current
都是与当前相机的视角有关
You can also combine image
你可以将图像跟踪
tracking with a World Tracking
与世界跟踪的配置结合起来
And in this case, you will have
在这种情况下
all the scene understanding
你可以获得所有与
capability available like Plane
场景理解有关的东西
Detection, light estimation,
像平面检测 灯光预估
everything else.
以及其他信息
So, what is more appropriate to
那这两种配置中
use which configurations?
哪一种更适合我们使用呢
Let's see.
让我们看看
So, in the
ARImageTrackingConfigurations
ARImageTrackingConfigurations is
是专门为围绕
really tailored for use cases
图像发生的 AR 体验
which are built around images.
所量身定制的
We can see an example on the
在屏幕的左侧 我们可以看到相应的例子
We can have an image that could
图像可以是
be a page of a textbook.
课本的某一页
And to make the experience more
为了让这次体验更
engaging, we are overlaying
吸引人 我们
dynamic graph.
动态地将图表重叠
In this case, on how to build an
在这个例子里就是
equilateral triangle.
如何画一个等边三角形
So, you can see that this
你可以看到
experience is really tailored
这个体验真的是为图像量身定制的
If you have, let's see this
让我们来看另一个例子
Image tracking is used to
图像跟踪用于
trigger some content that then
触发一些超出
goes beyond the extent of the
图像范围的内容
image.
在这种情况下 你需要使用
the ARWorldTrackingConfiguration
ARWorldTrackingConfiguration
as you will need the device
因为你需要设备的位置信息
position to keep track of that
来保持对图像外的
content outside the image.
内容的跟踪
Also, note that the image
因为图像跟踪并不使用
tracking doesn't use the motion
运动数据
data, which means it can also be
所以它适用于像
used on a bus or an elevator,
公交车或者电梯这类
where the motion data don't
运动数据与视觉数据
agree with the visual data.
不匹配的场景下
So, let's see now, how we can do
下面要讲的是
this in code.
如何在代码中实现这些功能
You can easily recognize those
你可以轻易地分辨出
three steps here.
这里的三个步骤
The first one is to gather all
第一个是收集所有图像
And there's a convenience
这里有个很方便的功能
function for that in the
ARReferenceImage 这个功能
ARReferenceImage class that
可以收集在
gathers all the images that are
特定群组中的
in a particular group.
所有图像
In this case, it's named Room1.
这个群组被命名为 Room1
We can then simply set the
我们可以简单的赋予
trackingImages property to those
ARImageTrackingConfigurations
images in the
中这些图像
ARImageTrackingConfigurations.
trackingImages 的特征
And run the session.
然后运行这一会话
You will then start receiving
你就能开始接收
the results, for example, to the
反馈 比如说在这个会话中
session:didUpdate anchors
didUpdate 这个锚点指定了方式
delegate method, where you can
你可以检查这个
check if the anchors is of type
锚点是否是属于
ARImageAnchor.
ARImageAnchor
In the anchor, you will find, of
在这个锚点中
course, the position and
你可以找到图像的
orientation of the image, as
位置与方向以及
well as the reference image
参考图像本身
itself.
你可能会问
the name of the image as you
那要怎样才能找到以
named it in the asset catalog so
你式命名的图像名称
that you know which image has
然后确认哪些图像被
been detected.
检测到了呢
There's also another Boolean
这里有一个叫 Boolean 的特性
property, which tells you if
它能告诉你这个
this image is currently being
图像当前是否
tracked in the frame.
正在被跟踪
Note here that other than these
除了我们现在
use cases that we have seen so
所了解到的使用例子外
far when you build experiences
当你围绕着
around images, image detection
图像进行建设
and tracking allows a few more
图像检测以及跟踪还有
things.
其他的功能
For example, if two devices are
就好像 如果两个设备都对着
looking at the same physical
同一张真实图像
image, you can detect this image
你可以在两个设备中
from both devices.
同时检测到这个图像
And this will give you a shared
这可以为你提供一个
coordinate system that you can
分享坐标体系
then use as an alternative way
这个体系可以为分享体验
to have a shared experience.
提供另一种选择
Another example, if you happen
另一个例子是 如果你刚好知道
to know where an image is
某张图像在世界上的
physically located in the world,
真实位置
like for example, you know that
比如说 你知道这幅公园地图
the map of this park is in the
在现实生活中的位置
You can use image tracking to
你可以通过图像跟踪来
get the position of the device
获得拍摄图像
with respect to the image and,
设备的位置
therefore, also the position of
还能获得这个设备
the device with respect to the
在这个世界上的位置
world, which, you can then use,
你可以利用这些数据
for example, to overlay
来找到真实世界
directions really attached to
中真正的方向
So, that concludes the image
有关图像跟踪的讨论
tracking.
就到此为止
Let's now go and look at the
接下来我们要讨论的是
Object Detection.
物体检测
So, with image tracking we have
通过图像跟踪 我们了解了
seen how we can detect images,
我们是如何检测图像的
which are planar objects in the
而图像在真实生活中
physical world.
是一个平面物体
Object detection extends this
物品检测将这个概念
concept to the third dimension
扩展到三维世界
allowing the detection of more
让检测常用物品成为可能
Note, though, that this object
但是这个物品
will be assumed to be static in
在场景中需要是静止的
the scene, unlike images that
它与图像不同
can move around.
检测图像时是可以移动的
We can see an example here.
我们可以看看这个例子
That's the Nefertiti bust.
这是娜芙蒂蒂胸像
It's a statue that could be
这是一个可以在
present in a museum.
博物馆中展览的雕塑
And now, you can detect it with
现在 你可以用 ARKit 来检测它
And then, for example, display
然后可以在真实物品的
some information on top of the
上方显示一些信息
Note also that in the object
ARKit 中的物品检测
detection in ARKit, we are
指的是有关物品的
talking about specific instances
真实实例的检测
So, we're not talking about
所以我们正在讨论的
detecting statues in general,
不是检测所有的雕像
but this particular instance of
而是检测这一特定的
the Nefertiti statue.
娜芙蒂蒂雕像
So, how do we represent these
我们如何在 ARKit
objects in ARKit?
中重现这些物体呢
You first need to scan the
首先你需要扫描这个物体
object.
事实上 只需要两步就可以
it.
完成这个检测
First, you scan the object and
首先 你对这个对象进行扫描
then you can detect it.
然后你就可以检测它
Let's talk about the scanning
让我们讨论一下扫描这一部分
part, which mostly is going to
对开发者来说
be on your side as a developer,
扫描这一部分主要是你们的责任
to basically, create that
你们需要负责
representation of the object
创造可用于
that can be used for detection.
检测的物体重现
Internally, an object is
从内在来看 这个物体
represented in a similar way as
的重现方式与
the world map.
世界地图类似
You can see an example of the 3D
在左边 你可以看到
feature points of the Nefertiti
娜芙蒂蒂胸像上的
statue there on the left.
3D 特征点
And to scan the object, you can
你可以使用扫描与检测 3D 物体
use the Scanning and Detecting
的开发者样本来
3D Objects developer sample
扫描物体
that's available on the website.
这个样本可在网站上获得
And note here, that the
需要注意的是
detection quality that you will
你在运行时的
get at runtime, later, is highly
检测质量很大程度
affected by the quality of the
上受扫描质量的影响
So, let's spend a few moments to
所以 不妨花上一些时间来
see how we can get the best
研究在扫描过程中
quality during the scanning.
如何才能获得最好的质量
Once you build and run this
一旦你建立并运行了
developer sample you will see
这个开发者样本
something like this on your
你会在你的设备上 看到与这个类似的东西
The first step is to find the
第一步是要找到你
region of space around your
物体周围的空间
The application will try to
App 会试图
automatically estimate this
自动估算这个
bounding box, exploiting
密封盒子的大小
different feature points.
探索不同的特征点
But you can always adjust this
但你可以随时通过
box by dragging on a side to
拖拽这个盒子的边框来
shrink it or make it larger.
调整它 使它变大或缩小
Note here, that what is really
有一点需要特别留意
around the object you make sure
当你围着这个物体扫描时
that you don't cut any of the
不能漏掉这个物体
interesting points of the
的任何特征点
You can also, rotate the box
你也可以从上方用两指手势
with a two-finger gesture from
对盒子进行旋转操作
So, make sure that this box is
你需要确保这个盒子
around the object and not
围绕着物体
cutting any interesting part of
而且包括了这一物体的
it.
所有特征点
The next part is the actual
接下来就是真正的扫描部分
In this phase what we want to do
在这个阶段
is really go around the objects
我们希望能真正的从各个
from all the points of view that
角度来观察这个对象
you think your users will want
任何你觉得你的用户可能会想要
to detect it later.
检测的角度都需要被考虑到
In order to make it easy for you
为了让你能更容易的
to understand which part of the
统计物体哪部分
objects have been, already,
已经被获取了
acquired like this beautiful
就像对这个美丽的
tile representation.
地板的重现
And you also can see a
你可以看到在顶部
percentage on top which tells
有一个百分比
you how many tiles have already
它能告诉你有多少块地板
been acquired.
已经被获取了
And it's really important in
在这个阶段中
this phase that you spend time
你需要在物体有着
on the regions of the object
许多特征点的 或者
which have a lot of features
有明显区别性的区域花上足够的时间
that are distinctive enough.
这是十分重要的
And you go close enough to
你需要走近对象去
capture all the details.
捕获所有细节
And again, that you really go
你还需要从所有
around from all the sides.
角度对对象进行扫描
Like you see here.
就好像你在这里看到的
Once you're happy with the
如果你对你已经获取的
coverage of your objects, you
信息感到满意了
can go to the next step, which
你可以进入下一步
is allows you to adjust the
你可以通过简单的拖拽
origin by simply dragging on the
在颜色系统中
coordinate system.
调整原点
And this will be the coordinate
这个系统将会
system that will be later given
是锚点在检测阶段时
to you at detection time in the
反馈给你的系统
anchor.
所以你要确保你将它
a place which makes sense for
放置在一个适合你的
your virtual content.
虚拟内容的位置上
So, at this point, you have a
现在 你已经有了
full representation of your
有关物体的完整重现
object, which you can use for
这个重现可以用来检测
And the application will now
现在 App 会转换到
switch to a detection mode.
检测模式
We encourage you to use this
我们强力建议你使用这一模式
mode to get early feedback about
以尽早获得有关
the detection quality.
检测质量的反馈
So, you may want to go around
你可能会想要
the object from different points
从不同的角度来观察这个物体
of view and verify that the
以确认这个物体
object is detected from all
已经从所有不同角度
these different point of view.
检测过了
You can point your device away,
你可以将你的设备移开
come back from another angle,
然后从另一个角度拿回来
and make sure that the scan was
你需要确保扫描质量好到可以
good to detect the object.
用于检测物体
You can also, move these objects
你也可以移动这些物体
around so that the light
这样 光照条件就会不同
And you want to make sure that
你需要确保在这些情况下
those are still detected.
物体还能被检测到
This is particularly important
对像玩具这样的物体而言
for objects like toys that you
这是十分重要的
don't know where they're
因为你并不知道
actually going to be physically
它们的真实位置
We, also, suggest that you take
我们也建议你将物体
the object and put it in a
放在一个完全不同的环境中
and still make sure that it is
但还能确保它能被检测到
In case this is not detected you
如果这个物体不能被检测到
may want to go back to the
那你可能需要回到
scanning and make sure that your
扫描环节重新扫描
environment is well lit.
并确保你所处的环境光线充足
We really like, well lit
光线充足的环境
environment during the scanning
在扫描时是至关重要的
If if you have a lux meter, it will
如果你使用的是 Verilux 灯泡
be about 500 lux will be best.
那 500 lux 是最佳的亮度
And if that is still not enough,
如果这个亮度也不够
you may want to keep different
你可能需要保存不同的
versions of the scans.
扫描版本
So, at this point, once you're
当你对检测质量
happy with the detection quality
感到满意时
you can simply drop the model to
你只需要将这个模型
your Mac and add it to the AR
存入你的 Mac 里
Resource Groups, just like you
并将它添加到 AR 资源群组中
did for the images.
就像你对图像所做的一样
Also note that there are some
有一些物体
objects that will work really
十分适合这个系统
Object like you can see on the
这些物体就像
left.
屏幕左侧展示的一样
First of all, they are rigid
首先 它们都是刚性物体
objects and they are, also, rich
纹理丰富
of texture, distinctive enough.
区分明显
But there are also certain kinds
但也有着一些
of object that will not work
物体不适用于这一系统
You can see an example of this
可以参考屏幕右侧的物体
And for example, metallic,
像金属的
transparent, or metallic or
透明的 或者金属的
reflective objects will not
反光的物体不适合用于
work.
这个系统
Or transparent objects like
透明的物体
glass material object will also
比如说玻璃材质的物体
not work because the appearance
也不适用于这个系统
of these objects will really
因为这些物体的外观
depend on where they are in the
受它们所处的场景影响
scene.
太大
So, that was how to scan the
这就是如何扫描物体
Again, make sure that you have
让我再强调一次
well-lit environment.
确保你的环境光线充足
Let's now see how we can detect
接下来要了解的是
this in ARKit.
我们如何在 ARKit 中检测到这一操作
If this looks familiar to you,
如果你觉得这个很眼熟
it's because the API is pretty
那时因为这个 API
similar to the one of the
与其中之一的图像十分相似
We have a convenience method
我们会有很方便的特征
to gather all the objects in a
来将所有对象集中到
group.
一个群组中
This time is in the
在这里 指的是
ARReferenceObjects class.
ARReferenceObjects 这一类
And to configure your
当你配置你的
ARWorldTracking configuration,
ARWorldTracking 参数时
you simply pass this object to
你只需要将这个对象
the detectionObjects property.
传输到 the detectionObjects 的特征下
Once you run the session, again,
一旦你开始运行这个会话
you will find your results.
你会收到结果反馈
And in this case, you want to
在这里 你会需要
check for the ARObjectAnchor,
检查 ARObjectAnchor
which will give you the position
它能为你提供现实生活中
and orientation of the object
物体的位置
with respect to the world.
以及方向
And also, the name of the object
物体的名字也会
as was given in the asset
在资产目录中得到展示
catalog.
你可能已经注意到
some similarities between the
物体检测与
object detection and the world
世界匹配重新定位之间
mapping relocalization.
有着某些类似之处
But there's also few
但它们也有着一些不同
So, in the case of the object
在物体检测时
detection we are always giving
我们是根据
the object position with respect
现实世界 赋予物体位置
While in the world map
而在世界地图的重新定位时
relocalization is the camera
是相机本身
itself that adjusts to the
调整了之前的
previous world map.
世界地图
In addition, you can detect
而且 你还可以检测多个物体
And object detection works best
物体检测十分适合
for objects which are tabletop,
那些在放置在桌面上
furniture sized.
家具大小的物体
While, the world map is really
而世界地图
the whole scene that's been
获取的则是整个场景
With this insight, we conclude the
以上便是有关物品检测的信息
Let's summarize what you have
让我们来总结一下我们
seen, today.
今天所讲过的东西
Orientation tracking tracks only
方向跟踪只能跟踪
the rotation of the device and
设备的旋转
can be used to explore statical
可以用于探索
environments.
静止的环境
World Tracking is the fully
世界跟踪是
featured position and
全特征的位置和
orientation tracking, which will
方向跟踪
give you the device position
它能根据世界原点为你
with respect to a world origin.
提供设备的位置
And enables all the scene
并启用有关理解场景的所有
understanding capabilities like
相关的功能
the Plane Detection, which will
比如平面检测
make you able to interact with
平面检测让你可以与真实的
the physical, horizontal, and
水平或垂直的平面互动
then put virtual objects.
你可以在这些平面上放置虚拟物体
We have seen how you can create
我们也了解了你可以通过
persistent or multiuser
框架中的保存和上传
experiences with the saving and
地图特征的功能创造
loading map features in the
一个持续的或者多用户的体验
And how you can detect physical
还有你如何才能用图像跟踪来
images and track them at 60
检测物理图像并以
frames per second with the image
每秒 60 帧的速度来跟踪它们
tracking and how you can detect
以及你是如何通过物体跟踪
more generic objects with the
来检测更多常用物体
And with this, I really hope you
我希望通过这个演讲
guys have a better
你们现在对 ARkit 中的所有
different tracking technology
不同的跟踪技术以及
that are present in ARKit and
它们是如何运作的
how they work behind the scenes.
有更清晰的理解
And how you can get the best
以及更了解你如何才能
quality out of it.
获得最佳的跟踪质量
And we're really looking forward
我们非常期待
to see what you guys are going
你即将利用
to do with that.
ARKit 所创造出来的作品
More information can be found at
更多的信息可以在
the session link in the
开发者网站上的
developer website.
演讲链接中获得
And we have an ARKit Lab
明天早上 9 点
tomorrow, 9 a.m.
将会有 ARKit 实验室的活动
We will both, me and Marion will
我和 Marion 都会
be there answering any question
在现场回答有关
on ARKit you may have.
ARKit 的任何问题
And with that, thank you, very
最后 十分感谢大家
much and enjoy the bash.
希望大家能享受这次知识冲击
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]